Inventory of the Fee and Murphy Family Papers, 1867-1931 (bulk 1889-1927)
University of Wyoming. American Heritage Center.
Fee and Murphy Family Papers
1867-1931
1889-1927
Fee and Murphy Family
00335
1.4 cubic ft. (4 boxes)
University of Wyoming. American Heritage Center.
The Fee and Murphy families came to Laramie, Wyoming, in the 1860s as employees of the Union Pacific Railroad. Family members also engaged in local politics and owned businesses, including a saloon. The collection contains business records of Michael H. Murphy and others and photographs of people and places in the vicinity of Laramie.
History of the Fee and Murphy Family
Michael H. Murphy (b. 1845) came to Wyoming in 1867 with the Union Pacific Railroad. He settled in Laramie, Wyoming, in 1871, where he operated a saloon, called Tammany Hall, at 301 First (Front) Street. He married May Fee (d. 1898) in 1873, and they had seven children: Thomas, Kate, Nellie, James, Edward, John, and George.
Lawrence and John Fee also came to Wyoming in 1867 with the Union Pacific Railroad and settled in Laramie. Lawrence Fee was town marshal and tax collector for the city of Laramie in the 1870s and 1880s and was a city councilman during the 1890s.
Scope and Content
The collection contains photographs of the Fee and Murphy families, their friends, and various places and events in and around the town of Laramie; business records, primarily of Michael H. Murphy’s saloon and other enterprises; and a small amount of personal material reflecting social life in Laramie or family concerns.
Access Restrictions
There are no access restrictions on the materials for research purposes, and the collection is open to the public.
Related Materials
There are no other known archival collections created by the Fee and Murphy Family at the date of processing.
Acquisition Information
The collection was received from family members in 1947 and ca. 1954.
Existence and Location of Copies
Digital reproductions of select portions of this collection are available at: http://digitalcollections.uwyo.edu:8180/luna/servlet/uwydbuwy~93~93.
Access Terms
Murphy, Michael H.;;; Laramie (Wyo.); Wyoming--History--To 1889.; Wyoming--History--1890-1918.; Wyoming--History--1919-1945.; Photographs.
Politics, Government, and Law; Business, Industry, Labor, and Commerce; Social Life and Customs; City and Town Life; Home and Family; Railroads; Wyoming
Container List
- Series I. Photographs, 1867-1927, undated
  - Automobiles, circa 1920s (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Baseball Team – “Tigers”, circa 1910 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Brotherhood of Locomotive Engineers – dance, 1904 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Carpenter (Judge and Mrs.), circa 1890s (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Coyotes in Traps (Harry Knight), 1920s (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Crawford, George and Jennie, circa 1880s (Box 1, Folder 5a)
  - Cusson, Eugene (Pastor of St. Laurence O’Toole 1872-1879), undated (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Deckelman, George (With Harry Joselyn and others, undated (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Doran, Pat and Pat Waglen – Laramie (Probably a later copy print), 1867 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Dunn Family, undated (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Elks Club Picnics, undated (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Fee Family (Elizabeth, Carrie, Jack, Lizzie, group including Terry, Dennis, Jack, Larry), 1898-1900, undated (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Fishing, undated (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Fleming Family, circa 1900 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Hardigan, J.J. – family hunting scenes, circa 1920s (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Hickey, Mamie, undated (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Holliday, Guy, undated (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Horses (Includes Steamboat, Tom Murphy’s horses Bent and Spent), circa 1920s, undated (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Hunting, 1919-1927 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Ivinson Home, Ivinson Memorial Bells, undated (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Laramie Businesses (Laramie Brewery, Callaghan’s Blacksmith Shop), undated (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Laramie Fire Companies (Railroad Hose Company 4 (dance), Rescue Hook & Ladder Company 1), 1893, undated (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Laramie Fires (Second Street, Windsor Livery Stables), undated (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Laramie Groceries (Laramie Grocery Company, Trabing, Pacific Market), circa 1878, undated (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Laramie Miscellaneous (1875 map, elk in stockyard), undated (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Laramie Refinery Explosion, undated (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Laramie Rolling Mills Crew, undated (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Laramie Streets – 3rd and Grand, circa 1900 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Laramie Tammany Hall Saloon, 1904, undated (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Laramie Vicinity (Vedawoo?), undated (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - McCollough Child, undated (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Michelson, Eva and Tena, circa 1900 (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Murphy, George, 1918, undated (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Murphy, James and John (Also friends and pet bear), circa 1900-1927 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Murphy, Kate, undated (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Murphy, Tom and W.H. (Also Guy Holliday and others), circa 1900 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Murphy Home, circa 1900 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Musicians – Lou Bath and others, undated (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Railroad (Union Pacific RR bridge over Laramie River, snow rotary, wreck), undated (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Railroad – Camp Peabody (Denver, Northwestern & Pacific construction survey), circa 1900 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Railroad – Snow Sheds at Rock River (Includes construction), 1917 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Reservoir (unidentified), undated (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Smart, Marie, circa 1900 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Stuhr, Ed, undated (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Unidentified Portraits, circa 1880s-circa 1900 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Unidentified Snapshots, circa 1920s (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Vedauwoo - Picnic at Veda Vu (sic), circa 1900 (Box 2, Folder 14a)
  - Woods Landing Saloon, undated (Box 2, Folder 15)
- Series II. Papers, 1878-1931
  - Business Ledgers – Saloon (?), 1890-1895 (Box 3)
  - Business Ledgers – Saloon (?), 1895-1909 (Box 3)
  - Correspondence – Personal and Business, 1889, 1905, 1925 (Box 4)
  - Dance Cards, 1891-1906 (Box 4)
  - Elks Lodge Memorial Service – Thomas Murphy, 1900 (Box 4)
  - Financial Records – Dreehouse, John and Oscar, 1909-1919 (Box 4)
  - Financial Records – Murphy, J.F. and Thomas, 1889-1927 (Box 4)
  - Financial Records – Murphy, M.H., 1883-1912 (Box 4)
  - Legal Documents – Dreehouse, John, 1909-1916 (Box 4)
  - Legal Documents – Murphy, M.H., 1882-1913 (Box 4)
  - Liquor Licenses, 1890-1904 (Box 4)
  - Miscellaneous Financial and Legal Documents, 1893-1931 (Box 4)
  - News Clipping – Mrs. John Fee, 1895 (Box 4)
  - Tax Receipts – Fee, Lawrence (signed by), 1878, 1881 (Box 4)
  - Tax Receipts – Murphy, M.H., 1882-1904 (Box 4)